Have you accidentally killed a plant?
And want to revive it?
Then why don't you set it on fire?
..and then freeze it.
Let it grow on the sun!
OR zap it!
Make it a fancy dinner.
Or feed it to a fish monster!
Or push it off a cliff!
Dance on it!
Explode it!-
Vomit on it!
Play with it underwater-
Stop it! You're only hurting it more!
I like the pool!
Where'd it come from?
It was huh... one of my
"funny-plant-revival" ideas.
So... just...
dunk it underwater?
Yep! Hopefully it'll work!
Did it work-
It did not.
After how badly we did at making a
suitable environment for the plants,
I didn't wanna take any chances with
how livable YOUR environment was.
I got this pool!
And I even got six new, shiny plates
for us all to use at the benches!
Wow, these plates are worth...
$10,000 shiny ones!
Yum!
Consider this pool useless. I just
want to look at these plates all day!
These are great!
One down, five to go!
NO! No more smashing Pillow.
Protect these for me Rocky.
BLEH!
It's time for break at plate!
ðŸŽµ Hey Two! ðŸŽµ
ðŸŽµ When you bake a cake ðŸŽµ
ðŸŽµ Decorate and take it to
the players who are safe ðŸŽµ
ðŸŽµ That's how you know it's Cake
at Stake ðŸŽµ
ðŸŽµ Cake At Stake ðŸŽµ
First up is Just Not for pouring
cursed water onto their plant!
Today's cake is ramen noodles!
They're long, secure, unrippable,
and perfect for bungee jumping!
Wow, it sure is crowded here with two teams...
Whatever!
Pillow, you are safe with 3,211 votes.
YUM! I deserve it!
Price Tag is the next safe with 3,172 votes.
I'll help with clearing out space up here, Two!
AHHHH!!!
Bomby, Nickel, and Cake are safe with
2,989, 2,970, and 2,854 votes respectively.
AHHHH!!! x3
And the last contestant safe on Just Not is...
Book!
With 2,822 votes.
WAH!!!
Phew...
Naily is out with 2,286 votes.
Onto Death Pact Again!
Marker is safe with 10,484 votes!
Your team can join in too!
Nice death prevention, Two!
Also safe are Black Hole and Tree, with
8,037 and 5,102 votes respectively.
I'll just jump off, Pillow. I get the deal.
Lightning, Fanny, and Remote. The
three of you are only separated by
a 16-vote difference, but only
two of you can be safe today!
Is it me? Am I safe?
You're lucky you are, or else this would
be awkward. You're safe with 5,043 votes!
Haha! Can't toss us!
Remote, Fanny. One of you got 5,038
votes. The other got 5,027 votes.
But which is it, huh? Which of- which
one- oh, who's it gonna be? Wow!-
I hate this!
Just tell us who is SAFE! HURRY UP!
Well, I hate to reward bad behavior, but
Fanny is safe with 5,038 votes.
Sorry Naily and Remote,
but you've been eliminated.
Well Remote, I think you NAILED it either way!
And I think you- remoted it.
Um-
Yeah that pun doesn't really work for my name.
Well I think you both twoed it!
...Doesn't work as well for my name, either.
Don't worry Two, I'll clear all these noodles up!
The beautiful plates! Where are they going?!
No! Not the steepest hill in the grasslands!
NO! Not the Zoomy Ramp of Yoyle Legend!
No!
Not the clouds accelerating at a faster pace to keep up with the Earth's faster rotation due to a sort of daylight savings change!
My bad!
NO! Not the Goiky Canal!
My plates!
My beautiful plates!
My–
My plaaaaaAAAAAAAAATES!
♫ Gibberish!! – coal bones ♫
Aaah!
With these plates missing, our living
quarters are approximately 40% less livable!
We'll be just like those Funny Plants in no time!
Today's challenge is to retrieve the five
beautiful plates from the
bottom of the Goiky Canal!
The two teams that do not retrieve
a plate will be up for elimination!
Go!
I HATE WATER! What is our strategy?!
Nothing fancy, folks.
We just dive in, hold our
breaths, and look for the plates.
Bit of a problem with that plan.
Yeah, how will you guys communicate?
That's easy.
I took a Yoyle Dance class that
taught me to speak through dance!
Here, read this book, and study up!
I HATE READING, but okay.
Done. Here!
Uh, okay...
Done.
No. The problem with the plan is that
you can't hold your breath forever.
What are you talking about?
If we didn't breathe, we'd die!
So, we'll prevent death by holding
our breath. Team Breath P.A.C.T.!
Wow.
It's genius.
Are you kidding me?
Hey, Strongest Team!
Robot Flower and I have been tinkering with an
invention that should come in handy for this!
They're breathable bubbles, which will
allow us to run and bounce about underwater!
Perfect for electrical ol' me!
HA HA HA HA!!
That is nothing compared to our invention!
The robotic fish monster!
Are You Okay, we'll simply use this machine
to drive into the water and find the-
WHAT?!
Ha! Shouldn't have gotten
cocky out there, Golf Ball!
It's our team's now!
Good luck, though!
Hey! That is unfair-
uh, wait. Where's TV?
(SCREAM!)
Guys, we kidnapped someone by accident.
Let me go, pretty please.
Sorry TV, you're officially in the hostage zone.
Hello TV!
Hello!
The canal! You all know what this means?
Swimming?
The Internet!
Folks, welcome to the Stuff
for Yourself online store!
Let's order a fishing rod!
Nice. Now let's grab that
plate! Uh, doesn't work, guys.
Of course it doesn't, you nincompoop!
That plate is miles underwater!
Thank you, Pin. What we actually need is-
A vacuum, of course.
Now we can suck up the water.
Uh, Coiny, why did you make us order that?
Grr! Okay! What we actually need is the world's
strongest magnet to suck up the plate to the surf-
Nope! We need to order a second moon! Moon 2!
We need floaties to help us swim!
Everyone, keep your pesky
hands away from the phone!
Done!
So, you ordered the Moon 2?
No, I did not order the moon.
I ordered the magnet, and uh-
GAH!
Curse your fiddly hands!
We ordered it to Yellow Face's
factory, which is 2,762 miles away!
2,76.. 2?
Yeah? Not everything is always the same distance.
We're gonna need to catch the nearest
train! We don't have much time, people!
Let's go, everyone!
Pillow! Today, you might've saved the day!
I always go out of my way to help others.
What?-
Uh, what were you saying, Cake?
Well, remember when all of us falling from the top
of the hotel caused a big splash in the
pool, and everything flew everywhere?
Oh! Are you saying we should drop from a
dramatic height and burst into the canal?
Exactly!
Just wanted to kill people.
You silly gooses! How can we get that
astronomically shastatomically high?
We don't have a scientist on our team.
How could we possibly build a contraption like
that? All we have is this debris from the canal!
Hm. Book! Define 'gravity'.
That definition sucks!
There! Let's start tossing
these, and fly into the sky!
Okay. Pillow, enough messing around!
Wha- Everyone! Follow that pillow!
What is this? The slowest train ever?
Well, I wish this was the fastest train ever.
Donut: Aah! Barf Bag! Undo this!
Hey! It's bad luck to undo your wishes.
Our fishy is gone!
No time to dwell!
Everyone, we must use Basketball's
pitiful breathable bubbles.
There's only six bubbles for their team, so
Puffball, you can sit this one out again.
Yo! Now that's the third time you've
treated Puffball badly! Back off, Golf Ball!
Oh Fries, you must understand that she is
not to be trusted! She'll sabotage our team!
Then how about Puffball and I
go sabotage the other teams?
Let's go, Puffball!
Okie dokie!
Eraser, you comin', bro?
Hmm... I'd rather mess with
Teardrop.
What's your plan, TD?
Last time you hung on a windowsill.
What's next, playing with a hose?
Wha?! No fair!
If this was like, a giant eraser or whatever,
I'd become part of that, too- if I could.
Hurry, Eraser! Just get in the water already!
After Teardrop!
After the robot fish!
Focus on the plates!
Anyone have any ideas? Winner?
Uh...
Let's fill Bottle with the lake!
Good idea, Icy!
Now the canal is dried up and dead!
YAY!
Uh, that's barely done anything.
Let's just get into the canal.
Here's a shovel! Why don't
you just dig under the canal?
HAHAHAHAHA! I doubt they'd fall for
that- wait, they're doing it?
This idea's grand! That was SO nice
of Fries to give us this shovel!
Ogh! I guess they DIED!!
TRY AGAIN, TEAM!
Finally... Now our strategy seems to be paying o-
ATTEMPT THREE!
Finally! The canal! Now we-
Maybe we should try something else.
Agh! I thought that'd work!
Help me...!
Icy! I'm so sorry! I- woah!
The water here is freezing!
Let's freeze the canal!
Then we could trap the other
teams underneath the surface!
Curse that stealing BASKETBALL thinking she can steal my inventions
while we're
left in these useless breathing bubbles!
Uh, try to embrace what we
already have, Golf Ball!
I think it's pretty cool!
No! I will not embrace it! It's terrible!
Woah! Be careful where you bounce!
That's it, Pen! You've crossed a line!
Don't hit Golf Ball like that!
Eraser! Put a stop to this madness!
Bro, give me a sec.
This place is huge! Where could it be?
Oh! Here's a package for you, Coiny!
Here we go!
...A world-ending bomb?!
Oh! G'uh- wrong package, hahahaha!
But why did you order-
Found it! The world's strongest magnet!
Ouch!
Status report, Snowball!
How's the team been doing?
Well, when I drove the fish, I smashed us
headfirst into a wall, and then straight
into the floor. Then I don't even know how this
happened: I got the fish back on land and drove
us around a bit. I ended up taking us through a
drive-thru, and now I'm here eating some fries.
How are they?
Not great. They prepared them for a fish.
And then we let Grassy control the robot,
and then he communicated with the nearby fish.
*clears throat*
I'm Grassy!
And then we let Bell drive.
I can't control it.
No! Bell, you can do anything!-- Uh,
she wasn't trying to be dramatic.
She genuinely just couldn't.
Looks like your leadership abilities
on this side have been disatrous,
Basketball. I've been keeping the hostage
in line, and TV's been fully cooperating.
Looks like Robot Flower's been
looking after him, if anything.
Robot Flower! They don't care
about us machines. We should
take down this fish before it gets out of hand.
Sorry, TV. I'm sticking with my team!
Robot Flower, trust me. Destroy it before it gets
out of control. Us mechanical
minds have to stick together.
No! I can't!
Just Not!
Just not what?
Over there, flying into the sky!
That's preposterous. I- oh, what the?! After them!
Hey, excuse me, how the heck is this possible?
Through the power of misdefinition,
anything is possible!
Puffball, attack!
Aah! Help me, help me, help me!
Pillow? You mind taking care of Puffball for us?
No worries! Bye, Bomby!
Help me, help me!
Goodbye and good luck!
Woah! Not cool.
Puffball! Start chomping!
Should we like, go join that mayhem, or nah?
Eh, I kind of like getting to have a break.
Besides, the juice is delicious!
Oh, can I try some?
Of course!
Well, that's just great!
Stop! The top is rock solid!
Bulleh!
I mean ice
solid.
Good work, Icy!
Now, we just wait for someone to swim on up!
Come back here, TD!
Huh? You want me to follow you?
Uh, okay? Where are we going?
Where are- oh my God!
The plates! You found them!
But why did you bring me here?
Uh, TD?
*Scary noises...*
Teardrop, where are you?
What?!
Okay, Pen! Cut it out!
Me? I haven't been in control
for at least 80 bounces!
This is exactly why we need to only have SOME
team members perform certain tasks, Tennis Ball!
Pen goofed off, and now
we're all paying the price!
Hey! You bumped me first,
and who made you the team leader anyway?
I'd be just as good as you!
I'd slap you, but the bouncing bubbles
are already doing a good job at that!
Guys! Help! A monster is
coming! Escape while you can!
What? Eraser, we're stuck here! Help us!
Quick! Pen, I've got two of the
plates! Let's get outta here!
You've got it, bro!
Lightning clouds!
Oh no! Look up ahead!
A DRAGON!
Easy to take care of. What's next?
Us! Your biggest foes yet!
With me and Puffball in the
way, there's nothing we can't-
Welp, didn't see that coming.
At least the worst is over-
And now it's just you and me, Pillow!
'm not worried! La la la la!
Let me down, Coiny!
Luckily, this magnet lets
you select what is attracted.
Here. Done!
Wait! Everyone, get onto the train, now!
Coiny, set the magnet to magnify the train!
What? But it won't move, and we'll be stuck here!
Trust me, Coiny, set it!
I got you!
Okay! See you soon, Coiny!
Good idea, Needle!
Don't call it a good idea! Call it a GREAT idea!
Wait, guys! The fish thinks
we're another fish monster!
Grassy communicated to the fish
earlier using this speaker!
Let's convince him to tell
us where the plates are!
It's working!
We're tricking him! Hehehe!
Wait, that's not cool. We
shouldn't be tricking him.
We're just using the robot to our
advantage. What's the problem?
It's one thing to use robotics
to aid us, but to deceive others?
No! We're not doing that.
It's fine. It's just a machine.
I'M just a machine!
I'm just Grassy!
I get that this must be
frustrating for you, Robot Flower.
Maybe you should just go hang with
TV until we're done with everything.
Or we could do this! Us robots
are taking you all down with us!
Robot Flower?! What are you doing?!
Us mechanical minds gotta stick together!
Robot Flower? TV? No!
Guys! We have to get out of here!
Yoink! I'll take that.
Two! This one goes to us. Thanks!
It sure does!
The S! are safe! Congratulations to all of you!
Bulleh!
Oh! I've got you!
Thank you, Lightning!
Brilliant! Death P.A.C.T. Again are also safe!
What's the goal, Pillow?
How is your sky staircase gonna
POSSIBLY help you win this challenge?
Because it might be fun to
sometimes mess with gravity,
but sometimes, it's fun to let
nature do its thing as intended.
Woah!
And here's a plate for you!
Nice! Just Not is safe!
Unlike those other teams, who are just not safe!
...What?
Hello, Teardrop(s)!
Wow! The teardrops are fading fast,
because you're safe once again, TD!
Only one more immunity is
up for grabs! Who will win,
Are You Okay, The Strongest
Team on Earth, or Team8s?
There's only one more shiny plate to save,
and it's almost too stressful to watch!
Snowball! See if you can open that hatch!
It's sealed shut! I think the machines
locked the doors! We're stuck!
No! I think this is finally gonna-
What?
EXPLO-
Oh. I thought it was going to explode.
Eh, I guess it didn't explode.
Well, the plate is right here,
but I can't win immunity! I need someone to
give it to me for their immunity to count!
Eraser! Go hand over that plate already!
Got it! Now just to hand it to you, and-
What?!
World's. Strongest. Magnet.
Here you go, Two! The plate is all safe and sound.
Thank you, Coiny! All the plates have
been retrieved, which means- viewers!
The Strongest Team on Earth. and Are
You Okay are both up for elimination,
but you only get one vote total,
so vote for one of them to stay in
the game. Make your one vote count!
Hi, it's me, Cary!
Alright, so that was TPOT 5.
Thank you so much for watching.
And this time, it looks like Are You Okay and
The Strongest Team on Earth
are both up for elimination,
so whichever member on both teams gets the fewest
votes from you, the viewers, will be eliminated.
It's just the sad truth of how things are.
Also, as we talked about in our
last video, yes, we're gonna be
having a BFDI and Inanimate Insanity meetup
in both Los Angeles and New York this year.
So if you've been watching our shows for a while,
I think it'd be really cool to
see you at one of our meetups.
Unfortunately, the New York one just sold
out, so there are no more tickets left to get,
but the Los Angeles one still has a
good chunk of tickets left to grab.
But also, let's not forget about this munchkin,
this Two plush! Because I know a
lot of you have questions about it.
The Two plushes will first be available
to buy at the actual meetup on location,
so if you come to the meetup, you'll be
the first ones to get your hands on these.
But if you can't come to a
meetup for whatever reason,
because you live far away or something like
that, they will be available to purchase
online after the meetups as well, so
everyone can get their hands on one.
But yeah, that was TPOT 5. Thank you to
Samuel Thornbury for managing this episode.
Also, I meant to say this last time,
but for the amazing TPOT Cake at Stake intro
that starts with "Hey Two, when you bake a
cake," that whole song, that was written by
Anko6theAnimator and animated by Highvan.
And I just think that, like, it was really
cool seeing them work together on such a,
you know, really cool song
and really fluid animation.
It was just a really great project. But yeah,
TPOT 5 has come to a close,
and I'll see you all in TPOT 6!
*Cries*